Keerthi Sagar, PhD

+353 874520896 | keerthisagar1989n6@gmail.com | Ireland (Stamp-4 Holder)

https://keerthisagarsn.github.io/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Robotics engineer with multi-disciplinary research and industry experience including specialization in robotics, planning algorithms, mechanical design, and fluid mechanics. Areas of expertise include:

- C++ & Python optimization, control algorithms
- Sensors & Mechanism Design

- Robot programming (Industrial & ROS)
- Effective technical & business communication

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Robotics Research Fellow2021-PresentKUKA RoboticsDundalk, IrelandIrish Manufacturing Research CLGMullingar, Ireland

- Software development and industrial testing of Sim2Real Robotic Welding with KUKA KR120 on rails
- Assistive real-time teleoperation control in medical device manufacturing using industrial robots (KUKA & Mecademic)
- Programming industrial and prototype systems using Siemens PLC's, SIMATIC HMI and ROS control systems.
- Implement machine Vision based visual-servoing and visual-inspection using Basler, RealSense cameras and OpenCV,
 HALCON libraries

Researcher 2018-2021
University of Genoa Genova, Italy

- Developed an intelligent tactile robotic gripper to demonstrate Human-Robot Collaboration windshield assembly process in Centro Ricerche Fiat, Italy. (Research Team)
- Designed and built a 7 DOF Stewart platform for Virtual-Reality Car & flight gaming experience (Design Team)
- Embedded programming and control of tensegrity snake-arm robots for probing and inspection
- Defined the software architecture and developed a Python software toolbox for robot manipulation "STORM"
- Motion planning and control of Mobile Manipulators involving Robot-Robot Coordination for sheet-metal fixturing EU
 FP7 project "SwarmItFix" using C++ and CAN protocol

Doctoral Internship 2017

Warsaw University of Technology

Warsaw, Poland

Coimbatore, India

 Developed planning algorithms using Integer-Linear Programming (ILP) and Hierarchical-Constraint-Satisfaction technique with backpropagation for swarm-like multi-agent mobile robots for aerospace fixturing application

Post-Graduate Engineer Trainee

Pricol Limited

2013

Designer for Indian TVS two-wheeler speedometers

- Responsible for customer interaction, product benchmarking, CAD modelling, 2D Drafting, DFMEA, Sample and Prototype making, Engineering Change Order (ECO) preparation
- Successfully optimized the number of coil windings for a two-wheeler fuel gauge variant leading to reduction in copper weight, hence a saving of 1.5 Million (INR) for every product variant in a year. Completed a PPAP process for an established speedometer product

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy in Mechanics, Measurements and Robotics Engineering University of Genoa	2014 - 2017 Italy
Master of Design (Mechanical Systems) (9.4/10) Indian Institute of Information Technology, Design and Manufacturing, Kancheepuram (Chennai)	2011 - 2013 India
Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering (83.4/100) Anna University (First Class)	2007 - 2011 <i>India</i>

CERTIFICATION

KUKA Programming P1 & P2 | Diploma in CAD |

CORE SKILLS

- CAD

Robot Software

- Optimization & Vision

Programming

Creo, CATIA V5, Inventor, CURA (3D Printing)
KUKA SIM, Unity, Delmia, Process Simulate, ROS-1&2
GUROBI, SciPy, PyTorch, OpenCV
C++, Python, Matlab, Git

LANGUAGE SKILLS

English (Proficient) | Italian (Basic) | Tamil (Native) | Hindi (Intermediate) | Telugu (Mother Tongue)

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Research Fellowship

 Awarded "<u>Marie Skłodowska-Curie</u>" grant of 200,000 EUR under Enterprise-Ireland's CareerFit-Plus Programme (2021-2024)

Doctorate

 Nominated for "<u>Best Paper</u>" award for the conference paper "Coordinated Selection and Timing of Multiple Trajectories of Discretely Mobile Robots" in 2018. (2018)

Post-Graduate

- "Best Project" award in Master of Design, (2013) batch for work on developing a "Miniaturized Flexible Flow Pump"
- "Indian-Ministry of Human Resource Development" scholarship for complete course of study (2011-2013)

Under-Graduate

- "National Winner", of the prestigious International Business Plan competition by India Future of Change (2010), amongst participants such as IIMA, B, C and Kellog School of Management. (2010)
- "<u>Finalists</u>" in the Business Plan event in the All-Asia Management Fest "Vishisth'10" held at IIT DELHI. The B-Plan summary presented in IIT-DELHI was published in the "ENTREPRENEUR" magazine May 2010 edition
- "<u>First-position</u>" for presenting the project "Micro Hybrid in Two Wheelers" in the National level Tech Fest "Impulse V2" at PSG Tech, Coimbatore. (2011)
- "Second-position" in the business plan event in National Level Tech Fest "Axis'10TechFest" held at VNIT-NAGPUR (2010)

High-School

 Ranked among the <u>top 10% scorers</u> in the "INTER LEVEL NATIONAL MATHEMATICS TALENT COMPETITIONS 2006" and secured a meritorious position in "MATHS OLYMPIAD 2001"

SELECTIVE SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS

- "Polytope-based continuous scalar performance measure with analytical gradient for effective robot manipulation", IEEE
 Robotics and Automation Letters, 2023 (Presented at IEEE-RAS ICRA, 2024, Yokohama, Japan).
- "Towards High Dynamic Operations with Parallel-Serial Robots", ASME 2024 IDETC, Boston, USA, 2024.
- "User-Centered Evaluation Framework for Telerobot Interface and Interaction factors--A Case Study on Medical Device Manufacturing", European Safety and Reliability Conference (ESREL 2023).
- "Hedra: A bio-inspired modular tensegrity robot with polyhedral parallel modules", International Conference on Soft Robotics, 2022.
- "STORM: Screw Theory Toolbox for Robot Manipulator and Mechanisms", IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2020.
- "Development of a Reconfigurable Four-Bar Mechanism for a Human Robot Collaborative Gripper", Advances in Robot Kinematics, 2020
- "The SwarmItFix Pilot" Flexible Automation and Intelligent Manufacturing (FAIM), Procedia Manufacturing, 2017.
- "Multi-goal path planning for robotic agents with discrete step locomotion" ASME 2017 IDETC, 2017.
- "Miniaturized Flexible flow pump using SMA Actuator" Procedia Engineering, 2013